TEENA M. TAUTKUS

94 Shenipsit Street Ellington, CT 06029 (860) 306-7876 (c) teena.tautkus@gmail.com

CONTENTS: PAGE 1: HIGHLIGHTS PAGES 2: STRENGTHS, MISSION, EMPLOYMENT HISTORY
PAGE 3-6: DETAILS PAGE 7: REFERENCES

HIGHLIGHTS

<u>Organizational Value</u>: I bring together leadership and operations for the achievement of the organization's mission through innovative solutions for sustainable success. I do this by helping people surpass their personal expectations to meet specific company goals.

SKILL SETS & CORE COMPETENCIES

• Executive support/liaiso	n •	Business operations
----------------------------	-----	---------------------

- Media liaisonBusiness developmentMergers/acquisitionsBusiness process improvement
- Organizational management/development
 Change management
 Team development
- Collaboration and negotiation Trainer, coach, mentor

EXPERIENCE OVERVIEW

Leadership/Operations (11+ yrs): Business management (7+ yrs), Operations (6+ yrs), Business development (5+ yrs), Public media liaison (3+ yrs).

Management/Supervision (11+ yrs): Senior staff development (5+ yrs), Employee development (8+ yrs), Training, coaching, mentoring (9+ yrs, 35+ employees)

Industries: Small and medium businesses, manufacturing, medical facilities, child-care environments.

RELEVANT WORK EXPERIENCE

Connecticut Women Obstetrics and Gynecology, LLC Practice Manager	2005 – 12/2010
Legrand North America Liaison to President & CEO	2002 - 2005
Veeder-Root Executive Assistant to President & CEO	1999 - 2002
Core Hypodermic Technologies Human Resource Manger	1997 - 1999

CERTIFICATION & EDUCATION HIGHLIGHTS

Certified Event Planner, Certified Personnel Coach	2002, 2009
Bachelor's Degree: Business Admin. & HR Management	1999
Associates: Business & Corporate Office Operations	1978

Strengths:

- Executive Support/Liaison
 Business Development
 Collaboration/Negotiation
 Business Operations
 Media Liaison
 Organizational development:

 Personnel management
 Diversity management
 - Employee relations
 - Corporate communications
 - Succession planning

- Executive staff coaching
- Staff Training
- Mentoring

Career Mission: To assume responsibility for the management and administration of a business venture, as a member of an exceptional executive staff. To apply my entrepreneurial experience and creative vision to promote excellence and innovative, sustainable growth, all within an environment where reliability, distinction and hard work are the standard.

- Provides leadership and direction to the management staff in the development of resources, programs and services to meet the short and long term business goals.
- Insights and solutions regarding the interpersonal interactions that affect core business operations.
- Provides leadership in the development, implementation, interpretation and maintenance of standards, policies and procedures, and to ensure product consistency and excellence.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Medical Practice Manager	CT Women OB/GYN, LLC	South Windsor, CT	2005- 12/2010
Special Assistant to Pres. & CFO	Legrand, North America	West Hartford, CT	2002-2005
Chief Administrative Executive (to President & CEO)	Veeder-Root (A subsidiary of Danaher Corp.)	Simsbury, CT	1999-2002
Human Resource Manager	Core Hypodermic Technologies	Farmington, CT	1997-1999
Chief Administrative Executive	Kelly Services	Farmington, CT	1996-1997
Founder/Director	Wee Folks Day Care Center	Hartford, CT	1994-1996
Chief Administrative Executive to Senior Financial Officers	Kidder-Peabody/PaineWebber	Hartford, CT	1989-1995
Real Estate Paralegal	Kahan, Kerensky, Caposella	Vernon, CT	1986-1989
Assistant Director	Verville Care Center	Vernon, CT	1984-1986

EXPERIENCE DETAIL

Medical Practice Manager

Connecticut Women Obstetrics and Gynecology, LLC

South Windsor, CT 06074 2005 – December 2010.

Following the sudden death of the practice owner in January 2010, I am currently serving to ensure all operational functions, and as liaison with attorneys with regard to the estate as it relates to the practice.

Other Responsibilities:

- Design, develop and implement annual sales/marketing/advertising campaigns.
- Manage communication between staff, physicians and patients.
- Oversight for scheduling in a changing medical environment.
- Crisis management and follow-up support.
- Negotiate and oversight of all third party vendor contracts.
- Ongoing office management of a medical practice with 5 physicians, 3 nurse practitioners, 1 ultrasound technologist, 5 medical support staff, and 5 office support staff.
- Established policies and procedures for patient records and office protocol.
- Responsible for hiring, training, and employee performance reviews.
- Trained new staff on all office processes.

Results: Increased patient base by 232% in first year of operation. Growth in revenue increased from \$200K start-up to \$2.2M.

Liaison to President & CFO

Legrand North America

West Hartford, CT 06110 2002-2005

- Leadership role with procurement team to choose vendors for cost savings.
- Primary U.S. Liaison with parent company, Legrand France, in fostering open relationships between all entities.
- Liaison with 4 company Presidents, 5 Executive Vice Presidents, 4 Chief Financial Officers, 13 support staff.
- Introduction/representation of Legrand as new parent company to four entities acquired through merger/acquisition.
- Event Planner for all major events and representation of company at each function.
- Managed the implementation of roundtable discussions with employees and Vision/Mission communications.
- Annual budget planning.

Results: Cost savings of 40% across all entities for all vendors. Fostered successful implementation of marketing formats that introduced Legrand North America as strong force in the lighting fixtures world.

Executive Assistant to President & CEO

Veeder-Root

Simsbury, CT 06070

1999-2002

- Implemented Policy deployment, strategic planning, organizational review, operations review structure as reporting system to parent company, Danaher Corporation.
- Liaison between 6 Executive Vice Presidents, 6 support staff.
- Direct line to Top 50 sales upper management and large Fortune 500 business customers.
- Time management of President's schedule.
- Annual budget planning.

Results: Addition of 3 major acquisitions to line leak detection equipment structure. Growth in sales to international markets in Brazil, UK, Germany, Canada.

Human Resource Manager

Core Hypodermic Technologies Farmington, CT 06032

1997-1999

- Executive liaison and assistant to President and CEO, CFO, Senior Accountant, Senior Sales Director, and General Manager.
- Responsibility for all HR functions for 40+ production floor staff.
- Implementation of company policies and procedures manual, employee handbook, safety manual, self-appraisal/performance evaluation process.
- Managed growth from 12 to 40 employees and designed company structure to implement a sales force, finance and marketing departments, plant operations and product development.
- Organized monthly employee events to foster morale and promote positive interaction between upper management and workforce.
- Served as Plant Manager during a 2-month vacancy.
- Planned and led executive staff meetings.

Results: Established operational controls to reduce waste and improve efficiencies to increase first year growth by 400%.

SELECTED PROFESSIONAL ACCOMPLISHMENTS

- Business Profitability/Crisis Management: Upon the sudden and tragic death of the primary physician and owner of the medical practice, both staff and patients were thrown into an emotional crisis. The physician was a leader in the medical community, as well as to the public, having been active in local organizations, both civic and professional. He was my close professional friend for over five years. The situation posed considerable risk to the solvency of the practice since many of the patients believed they needed to seek other alternatives for their health care. Solution: Staff received grief counseling. They were trained and mentored to work with patients who were also suffering from the loss. I launched an advertising campaign, distinguishing the practice as the point of focus for the community to pull together through the tragedy. Results: The practice maintained a strong leadership role in the community, becoming the center for healing from the tragedy. Professional services were maintained and less than 1% of clients sought healthcare elsewhere.
- Business Transition—Human Resource Management: Hired to oversee the merger of two medical practices, and given one month to create an organizational structure, my presence was seen as a threat to the job security of the existing staff. Solution: Through the repeated message that "consistency of patient care" was a priority, and that existing staff would be needed to ensure that goal, I was able to establish a trust and rapport with staff. Through personal meetings, careful listening, and a genuine desire to build a better practice, the team worked together to embrace a new Policies and Procedures Manual and take personal ownership and responsibility for their role in patient success. Clear performance expectations, compensation structures, bonuses and rate increases that were directly tied to performance were launched for the entire staff. Results: Retention of existing staff. Daily operations of the satellite practice increased in efficiency and functionality.
- Branding/Business Expansion: A women's healthcare practice, with an all female staff, was purchased by a male physician. This posed a new challenge since the existing brand and advertising read, "All women for women." The existing patient base was unaccustomed and uncomfortable with the presence of a male physician. Patient/Doctor relationships were strained. Solution: A former employee of the physician, a female Nurse Practitioner, was hired. She brought an assurance to the patients. Solution: I conducted a demographic study and subsequently hired two additional practitioners to match the existing and expected future patient population. An advertising campaign of 26 bi-weekly clips with photos of all practitioners introduced the new brand, "New Choices and a Team that Works." An Open House was organized with invitations sent to all patients, town officials, local chamber of commerce, and community. Initiation of new healthcare programs specifically maintained by the male practitioner was unveiled, introducing him as the expert in his field. Results: Increase in patient base by 232% in first year of operation.

- Acquisition Management/Profitability: Legrand North America was formed through the acquisition of four separate manufacturing companies, all of which were associated with lighting fixtures. Three were located in various parts of Connecticut and the fourth was located in New York. The result was a company of over 500+ employees, with four different sets of processes, independent vendor contracts for office supplies, executive travel, vehicle rentals, etc., which contributed to excessive overhead.
 Solution: I charged a procurement team with the task to identify and eliminate areas of duplication amongst the four companies. Following a cost benefit analysis, I established a vendor bidding process. Then I negotiated volume discounts with vendors and established processes to ensure the best pricing schedules. Results: Overall cost savings to Legrand NA: 40% lower than the collective costs between the four companies for the top 20 expenditures.
- **Profit & Loss/Diversity Management:** A manufacturing company with 12 line-workers who spoke Hungarian, Polish and Spanish, but very little English, were hired by the President and CFO prior to my arrival as HR Director. The company struggled with language barriers and lack of organizational structure. The Plant Manager and Executive level management was extremely frustrated as product quality continued to be below standard. **Solution:** Through an organizational restructuring process, I hired bi-lingual Floor Supervisors, who reported to the Plant Manager. **Results:** An immediate reduction in waste and higher efficiency increased company profit margins. The rise in employee morale and loyalty brought quality workmanship, raised retention rates and reduced turnover.
- Operational Effectiveness/Quality Control: After a few months of operation, Core Hypodermic, a small company of 12 employees that manufactured needles for medical use, was late on product delivery and was not able to meet FDA quality regulations. Each of the top four executives functioned in multiple roles. Solution: I hired a plant manager and 28 employees; established quality standards, which were regularly monitored. Then I ensured proper documentation of policies and procedures accompanied with accountability measures. These were published and verified through job evaluation. I personally conducted performance evaluations to ensure that safety guidelines were met. Through weekly meetings of the leadership, we were able to monitor progress against measurable standards. Results: Operational efficiencies and quality control reduced waste and increased growth by 400%. A proven track record of on-time delivery established strong client confidence.

Organizational	
Effectiveness	

Visionary: Ability to provide leadership that integrates operational consistency with employee excellence. "The company mission becomes the foundation that draws me to envision operational processes, which when combined with the flow of human resources, bring value and focus to the direction of the organization."

Philosophy: "Fostering strong working relationships bring a cohesiveness that drives teams towards creativity as a tool to identify and implement sustainable growth patterns."

Leadership Style

Shared accountability/trust and respect:

"I lead by example first and foremost. I can be direct without confrontation when dealing with behavioral and interpersonal matters. I take accountability for my actions and expect others to do the same. I want to be informed, but I give people the freedom to get the job done."

Organizational Management

Philosophy: Structure is important in defining expectations that lay a foundation by which people can excel.

Process: "I make it a practice that individuals are valued and their work and presence brings value to the company. I believe this makes for a winning formula for achievement".

EDUCATION & TRAINING

Certificate: First-Aid (including CPR) American Red Cross, West Hartford, CT	2010
Certificate: Personnel Coach Dream Coach University, San Francisco, CA	2009
Certificate: Event Planner Online Course: Lovegevity.com	2002
Bachelor's Degree: Business Admin. & HR Management Belford University, Wilmington, DE	1999
Certificate: Real Estate Law Hartford College for Women, Hartford, CT	1978
Associates: Business & Corporate Office Operations Morse School of Business, Hartford, CT	1978

CIVIC AFFILIATIONS

Greater Hartford Women's Conference, Chairman, 2010-2011
South Windsor Chamber of Commerce, Board of Directors, 2010-2011
Susan G. Komen, Race for a Cure, Town Chairperson, 2010
Incredible Life, Co-author, 2010
Mary Jones Show, Believe Team, 2009-present
Re-create Your Future Now Conference, Chairman, 2009
Tips from Teena on Tuesdays, Radio, 2009
Baseball Booster Club Secretary, 1999 and Baseball Booster Club President, 2001-2003
Light the Night Breast Cancer Fundraiser, 2000
Citizens Police Academy Graduate, 2000
IAAP Member, 2000-2005
Nutmeg Big Sister, 2001

REFERENCES

Mr. Scott Clawson

President & CEO - GSI, Inc. (Former CEO of Veeder-Root) (217) 246-7966 (c) sclawson@gsiag.com

Ms. Anne Marie Capossela

Bookkeeper/Administrative Assistant (Former direct report) (860) 870-8104 (h) amcapossela@sbcglobal.net

Ms. Cate Evans

Former Executive Director, South Windsor Chamber of Commerce (Personal business reference)
(860) 965-9442 (c)
(860) 648-9579 (h)
marketingorganizers@cox.net

Ms. Debra Smith

Proforma/GraphicWorks (Third-party Vendor) (860) 836-7370 (c) debra.smith@proforma.com

Ms. Mary Jones

Radio Personality - The Mary Jones Show (Co-author and co-radio host) (860) 748-1918 (c) mary@maryjonesshow.com

Ms. Paula Bagge

Sonography Associates, Sonographer (Former direct report) pmbagge@comcast.net (413) 348-2139 (c)